<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Let&#39;s decarbonise. on Electrify Canberra</title>
    <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Let&#39;s decarbonise. on Electrify Canberra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Q: Who is Electrify Canberra?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/1/</guid>
      <description>A: Electrify Canberra is a dedicated group of local people who share a passion for big ideas and positive change, working together on a voluntary basis. When we got word that Canberra could be the home of the electrification pilot, we came together to try to mobilise our community to bring it about.
We’re working closely with Rewiring Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q: Who is Rewiring Australia?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/3/</guid>
      <description>A: Rewiring Australia was launched in 2021, founded by engineer / energy expert / The Big Switch author, Dr. Saul Griffith.
Rewiring Australia illustrates the positive climate and economic outcomes possible for Australia, and the world, with an ‘electrify everything’ strategy. They’re working with government agencies, business, industries, investors and other stakeholders to try and electrify all households in Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Q: What exactly is ‘an electrified household’?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/4/</guid>
      <description>A: Practically, in the average Australian household there are 6 things that could be transitioned to electric - rooftop solar, a home battery, cooking, heating your home, hot water and an electric vehicle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Q. What is the purpose of the pilots?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/5/</guid>
      <description>A. By connecting all the homes in a street or suburb, these pilots will do much to prove that climate action makes environmental and economic sense.
We’re mobilising interest in our community. We are working to demonstrate that we have enough households in a concentrated area ready to make the transition to electrification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Q: Where is the funding coming from?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/6/</guid>
      <description>A: We don’t know the exact subsidies and benefits that will be offered yet, but the program will be heavily subsidised to make it compelling and affordable for as many households as possible.
Electrify 2515, together with Rewiring Australia, is campaigning for funding from government agencies such as the Australian Renewable Energy Agency and the Clean Energy Finance Corporation, state governments, and industry such as vehicle companies and appliance manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Q. What is being offered to households included in the pilot?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/7/</guid>
      <description>Appliances and Home Battery: As part of the proposed program, you would receive the electric home appliances you need free of charge - induction cooktop, split system air conditioner and heat pump hot water heater. You would also be supplied with a home battery. You would be able to keep these items at the end of the 2 year trial.
Rooftop Solar: If you don’t already have a rooftop solar system you would be provided one at a heavily subsidised price.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Q: Do participants get to keep the electrified items?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/8/</guid>
      <description> A:Under the draft program:
Appliances and Home Battery: You can keep the appliances and home battery. Rooftop Solar: You can keep the rooftop solar system. Electric Vehicle: You can choose to purchase the electric vehicle at a discounted price or return it. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Q: Is the electric vehicle free?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/9/</guid>
      <description>A: We don’t expect it will be - it will most likely be offered under a lease for the 2 year pilot program.
The draft proposal is a leasing charge of 4 cents per kilometer to use the EV (for comparison, the average petrol vehicle costs 20 cents per kilometer to run), and you would have the option to purchase the EV at a discounted price at the end of the 2 year trial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q: How many households do you need to register?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/10/</guid>
      <description>A: The search is on to find a community willing and able to test an electrification pilot. We need to show that there is a compelling number of households connected to our local grid willing to do so.
500 households is the minimum number required to be considered. The goal is closer to 2,000 households which will demonstrate the technical and social viability of the program</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q:  How will this lead to savings in cost of living?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/11/</guid>
      <description>A: Electrifying our homes will not only slash our emissions it will also save households money on energy bills (p.89). By 2030 an electrified household will save on average $5000 per year on their energy and fuel costs. Lower-income homes spend a higher proportion of their pay cheques (nearly double) on energy costs (p.95)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q. What happens if households refuse to participate?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/12/</guid>
      <description>A: As long as more than 60-70% of freestanding households enroll, the pilot will be a rigorous test of electrification. The minimum grouping of households would be the 50 or so houses that take power from the same distribution transformer. (p.143) A larger pilot would aggregate households connecting to adjacent distribution transformers. The goal would be to scale a pilot so that it included every house connected to the neighbourhood substation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q. What about renters, apartment dwellers and people that don’t drive a car, how can they benefit from electrification?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/13/</guid>
      <description>A: The financial structure of the pilots can be designed to include everyone in the community, even those that do not have a car or roof space for solar. The financial benefit that comes from replacing gas and grid electricity with cheap, locally produced solar can be shared. The way to make this work is that all households would sign up to an electricity retailer that is participating in the pilot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q. Can renters participate in the project?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/14/</guid>
      <description>A: Yes, for a renter to get involved and see the benefits of reduced energy bills, they would need to work in partnership with their landlord (who will see the benefit of efficient appliances installed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q. What is a householder doesn’t want or need one of the electrified household items?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/15/</guid>
      <description>A: No problem. Just take the things you need and leave the rest. However, Rewiring Australia would require that you transition away from gas for at least one household appliance - cooking, heating your home and/or hot water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q. How will data be collected?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/16/</guid>
      <description>A: Data will be collected through a smart meter that would be installed on your fuse box. Your data will be protected by Rewiring Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q: When with the pilot start?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/post/17/</guid>
      <description>A: Rewiring Australia would like to select a pilot community in the first quarter of 2023 and begin rollout in mid 2023.
2022 - 2025: Pilots to showcase the technology Australia is the place to make electrification happen first. We have the institutions, technology and successful love affair with rooftop solar. But with any change, we need to show people how it works and iron out any issues before we move towards the mass electrification of the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a world-first pilot program</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/about_the-_programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/about_the-_programme/</guid>
      <description>This proposed pilot program would assist a whole community to make the switch; that is, generously subsidise and support participating households to go electric in six important ways (see below). The exact details of the program are still being determined, but could look something like this:
Over a two-year period, Rewiring Australia will supply a household with the electrified appliances they don’t already own, and lease them an electric vehicle. This would cut the average household’s running costs by 30%, saving people thousands on their energy and fuel bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>electrify everywhere:</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/electrify_everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/electrify_everywhere/</guid>
      <description>Let’s electrify everywhere! Let’s electrify everywhere! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>other initiatives?</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/relations-to-other-programmes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/relations-to-other-programmes/</guid>
      <description>How do we fit in with other initiatives?
Suburb Zero Pilot and the National Electrification Program (NEP) The smart-energy transition and household electrification will lead to lower bills, fewer emissions and more jobs.
I advocate an Australia-wide National Electrification Program (NEP), starting with a demonstration project in Canberra to create the world’s first fully electrified suburb, to be developed in conjunction with Saul Griffith and Rewiring Australia.
The ‘Suburb Zero’ trial would see $20 million of federal government funding leverage $50 million of private sector capital for a two-year, opt-in pilot program that guarantees participating Canberran households a 20-25 per cent saving per year on their fuel and energy bills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>six things to electrify:</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/six-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/about/six-things/</guid>
      <description>Six things to electrify: Rooftop solar Solar panels mean your home can generate its own power. Rooftop solar electricity is about five times cheaper than grid prices. A home battery Solar panels can charge up a home battery while the sun shines. Then the battery can help power your home through the evening. (You&amp;rsquo;re still connected to the grid for cloudy days when you need more energy.) Cooking Induction cooking uses around half the energy required by fossil fuel methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gjolleyrogers.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>The Electrify Canberra initiative is 100% volunteer-driven. This website is administered by the Electrify 2515 Committee - a group of local people from all walks of life, dedicated to advancing climate action in our own community and throughout Australia.
If you’re keen to express your interest in the program and stay updated on progress, please complete a short Survey 1.
Have further questions? You can contact us at electrify2515@gmail.com or complete this form.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
